Julien Plu

My name is Julien Plu, I am passionated by different things. My strongest passion is about computers since I had my first one at 6 years old. Besides computers, I love also doing sport, like tennis that I practiced for 11 years and scuba diving that I practice since more than 20 years. Another passion is music, I love playing guitar since more than 5 years, I play mainly hard rock and metal music but I also like any kind of other music. As most of the persons of my generation, I love video games since my youngest age, any kind of video games. The last but not the least of my passions is, traveling, every year I try to visit two or three countries abroad France, mainly for doing scuba diving.

EXPERIENCES

2018-04 present

Applied Scientists

Paris, France

· My role at Leboncoin is to investigate new approaches and ideas involving machine learning in order to improve the experience of our users.

2018-01 2018-03 **R&D Engineer**

Paris, France Mondeca

• Help to develop the internal sofware of the company on Semantic Web technologies.

2014-07 2017-12 PhD candidate

♥ Sophia-Antipolis, France Furecom

· My PhD topic is to extract lexical units (entities) from textual documents to disambiguate them against Web resources contained in a knowledge base and in an adaptive manner. This adaptivity is on the language of the processed texts, the used knowledge base and the textual content that can be either formal text (journalistic style) or informal text (microposts).

2013-04 2014-06 **Software Engineer**

♀ Sophia-Antipolis, France Aepsilon

· Consultant at Orange on semantic Web, NLP and Machine Learning technologies for their in-house Web search engine. My works was about to implement a natural language question module. Take a question in natural language and turn it into a SPARQL query to provide an answer and to put DBpedia technologies into Orange production pipeline. I also prototyped a French entity relation extraction system from crawled Web pages in order to populate a knowledge base.



SELECTED PROJECTS

2014-07 present

- **ADEL**
- · ADEL stands for ADaptive Entity Linking. It is the output of my thesis. It is developed in Java (Spring, Spring boot and Spring Cloud)
- The code can be found at: https://github.com/jplu/ADEL

2016-12 present **DeepNER**

- · DeepNER is a Named Entity Recognition approach that uses a Deep Learning architecture developed during my PhD. It is developed in Python with Tensorflow
- The code can be found at: https://github.com/jplu/DeepNER

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science 2017

♥ Sophia-Antipolis, France

Master in Computer Science (AI speciality) 2012

♥ Montpellier, France University of Montpellier II

License in Computer Science 2010

University of Montpellier II ♥ Montpellier, France

Scientific baccalaureate 2017

> High School Joliot Curie Sète, France

Contact Info

in linkedin.com/in/julienplu

@ plu.julien@gmail.com

**** +33 6 70.14.19.68

34 rue Lenine

93170, Bagnolet, France

Portfolio

Attps://jplu.github.io

A https://github.com/jplu

Skills

Research Areas

Natural Language Processing Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Semantic Web

Languages

Java

Python

Go

C and C++

Frameworks

Java: Spring, Spring Boot, Spring

Cloud, Stanford CoreNLP

Python: Tensorflow, Numpy,

Pandas, scikit-learn Go: Gin, cobra, viper

Web Development

VueJS

Operating Systems

Linux

Windows

Mac OS

Miscellaneous

Docker

Kubernetes

Google Cloud Platform